<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
<comment>Irrigation experiment server configuration</comment>
<!--<entry key="hostname">localhost</entry>-->
<entry key="hostname">@SERVER_ADDRESS@</entry>
<entry key="port">@PORT_NUMBER@</entry>
<entry key="round0">round0.xml</entry>
<entry key="round1">round1.xml</entry>
<entry key="round2">round2.xml</entry>
<entry key="round3">round3.xml</entry>
<entry key="round4">round4.xml</entry>
<entry key="round5">round5.xml</entry>
<entry key="round6">round6.xml</entry>
<entry key="round7">round7.xml</entry>
<entry key="round8">round8.xml</entry>
<entry key="round9">round9.xml</entry>
<entry key="round10">round10.xml</entry>
<entry key="round11">round11.xml</entry>
<entry key="round12">round12.xml</entry>
<entry key="round13">round13.xml</entry>
<entry key="round14">round14.xml</entry>
<entry key="round15">round15.xml</entry>
<entry key="round16">round16.xml</entry>

<entry key="wait-for-participants">true</entry>
<entry key="number-of-rounds">17</entry>

<entry key="q1">49</entry>
<entry key="a1">49%</entry>
<entry key="explanation1">An existing infrastructure efficiency of 20% + 29 tokens invested = 49% infrastructure efficiency.</entry>
<entry key="q2">5</entry>
<entry key="a2">5 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation2">
<![CDATA[
An existing infrastructure efficiency of 35% + 15 tokens invested = 50% infrastructure efficiency for the current round.  
An infrastructure efficiency of 50% corresponds to a water delivery capacity
of 5 cubic feet per second.
]]>
</entry>
<entry key="q3">5</entry>
<entry key='a3'>5 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation3">Since there is only 30 cubic feet per second of water
available, the irrigation infrastructure capacity of 35 cubic feet per
second will not be fully used.  When A opens their gate, they take 25 of the
30 cubic feet per second out of the canal, leaving 5 cubic feet per second for
B.
</entry>
<entry key="q4">25</entry>
<entry key="a4">25 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation4">If A has 25 cfps available and does not take any
water, the same amount is available for the people downstream. Since B, C and
D do not take water, 25 cfps is available for E.</entry>
<entry key="q5">7</entry>
<entry key="a5">7 tokens</entry>
<entry key="explanation5">If you invest 7 out of 10 tokens, you keep 3 tokens for yourself. If you apply 202 cubic feet of water to your field you will earn 4 tokens. 3 + 4 = 7 tokens </entry>
<entry key="q6">19</entry>
<entry key="a6">19 tokens</entry>
<entry key="explanation6">If you invest all 10 tokens, you keep 0 tokens from
your initial endowment.  If you apply 555 cubic feet of water to your field
you will earn 19 tokens. 0 + 19 = 19 tokens.</entry>

<entry key='final-instructions'>
<![CDATA[
<p>
The experiment is almost over.  We have a brief survey for you to fill out while the
facilitator prepares your payments.  When the facilitator has finished preparing
payments and you have all completed your surveys your computer number will be
called.  You can then go next door to receive your payment.  For privacy reasons we
must pay you one at a time. 
</p>
<p>
Thanks for participating!
</p>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="initial-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<p>
You have already earned 5 dollars by showing up for this exercise. You can earn
more, up to an extra 25 dollars. You will participate in this exercise as a part of
a group of five participants. Your group has been formed by randomly assigning you
to FOUR other participants in the room. 
</p>
<p>
The amount of money you earn will depend on the decisions made by you and the other
members of your group. This exercise mimics decisions people make in irrigation
systems. In each round you will receive 10 tokens which you can invest in the
irrigation infrastructure. Given the capacity of the irrigation infrastructure and
the availability of water, you can grow crops. Tokens earned in a round is the sum
of tokens not invested plus tokens earned by growing crops. Each token is worth 5
cents. In each round you will first make a decision as to how much to invest in the
irrigation infrastructure. Based on the combined contributions of all 5 participants
in your group in each round, your group can maintain the capacity of the irrigation
infrastructure for growing crops. 
</p>

<p>
We will now start a practice round to help illustrate the experiment.  Before each
round in this experiment you will have a chat period of 60 seconds where you can
send text messages to the other participants. You may discuss any aspect of the
exercise with two important exceptions:
</p>
<ol>
<li>You are <b>not allowed</b> to promise the other participants
side-payments or threaten them with any consequence after the experiment is
finished.
</li>
<li>You are <b>not allowed to reveal your real identity</b>.</li>
</ol>
<p>
We will be monitoring the chat traffic.  If we detect any violation of these rules,
we will have to remove <b>all members of the group where the violation occurred</b>
from the experiment. That group will have to wait until the entire experiment is
finished to receive their payment.
</p>
<p>
You will see a text box appear on your screen when a chat period starts. The amount
of time left in the chat period will be displayed <b>below the chat messages window</b>.<br>
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key='game-screenshot-instructions'>
<![CDATA[
<img src="http://dev.commons.asu.edu/irrigation/images/game-interface-screenshot.jpg">
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="facilitator-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Facilitator Instructions</h3>
<p>
Welcome to the facilitator interface.  This interface allows you to control
the experiment.  You may only modify configuration parameters <b>before</b>
you start the experiment by selecting the Configuration menu.  When all the
participants are ready to begin the experiment, you can start the experiment
by selecting Experiment -&gt; Start.  After a round has been completed you
will be able to view the statistics for all of the participants.  You can
begin the next round by selecting Round -&gt; Start.
</p>
]]>
</entry>



<entry key="welcome-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<center><h3>Welcome to the experiment.  Please do not close this window or open any
other applications.</h3></center>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="quiz-page1">
<![CDATA[
<p>
The first two questions deal with irrigation infrastructure investment.  
<b>Please refer to Table 1 of your handout</b>.
</p>

<form>
Question 1:<br>
Given an existing infrastructure efficiency of 20%, if the five participants invest
a <b>total of 29 additional tokens</b>, what is the new irrigation infrastructure
efficiency?<br>
<input type="text" name="q1" value = "">%
<br><br>

Question 2:<br>
Suppose the infrastructure efficiency in the last round was 60%.  For the current
round, the efficiency will decline by an amount of 25% for a resulting
infrastructure efficiency of 35%.  If the members of your group invest a total of 15
tokens, what will be your group's resulting water delivery capacity?<br>

<input type="text" name="q2" value = ""> cubic feet per second
<br><br>

<b>The next two questions deal with the capacity of the irrigation system in relation
to the actual amount of water available.</b>
<br><br>
Question 3:<br>
If the irrigation efficiency is between 71 and 80%, the water delivery capacity of
the irrigation system is 35 cubic feet per second.  Suppose the water supply
available to your group is 30 cubic feet per second and A opens their gate,
diverting water at 25 cubic feet per second.  What is the available water flow for
B?
<br>
<input type='text' name='q3' value=''> cubic feet per second
<br><br>
Question 4:
If the available water delivery capacity is 25 cubic feet per second and A, B, C,
and D are not using water, how much cubic feet of water per second is available for
E?<br>
<input type='text' name='q4' value=''> cubic feet per second
<br><br>

<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit"><br>
<br>

]]>
</entry>

<entry key="quiz-page2">
<![CDATA[
<p>
The final two questions cover the number of tokens you can earn in within a round.
<b>Please refer to table 2 of your handout</b>.
</p>
<form>
Question 5:<br>
If you invest 7 of the 10 tokens you start with and you apply 202 cubic feet of
water to your fields, what is the total number of tokens you will have earned at the
end of the round?<br>
<input type="text" name="q5" value="">tokens
<br><br>
Question 6:<br>
If you invest all 10 tokens you start with and you apply 555 cubic feet of water to
your fields, what is the total number of tokens you will have earned at the end of
the round?<br>
<input type="text" name="q6" value="">tokens
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key='water-collected-to-tokens-table'>
<![CDATA[
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Water applied to your field</th>
<th>Tokens earned</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 150</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>150-199</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>200-249</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>250-299</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>300-349</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>350-399</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>400-499</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>500-549</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>550-649</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>650-699</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>700-749</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>750-799</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>800-849</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>850-899</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&gt; 899</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="investment-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Invest tokens in the irrigation infrastructure</h3>
<p>
You have been endowed with 10 tokens to invest. You must make a decision about
how much you wish to invest [0,10] in the irrigation infrastructure.  You can
see the relationship between total investment and irrigation infrastructure in
the table below.  After you have entered the number of tokens you'd like to
invest, hit the enter key or click the submit button to confirm your
investment. When everybody has made their decision, the total investment will
be calculated and the overall irrigation infrastructure will be displayed.
Each token you invest corresponds to one percent of infrastructure efficiency,
so if you invest 10 tokens you are contributing 10% to the overall
infrastructure efficiency.
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Total Infrastructure Efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery (cubic feet per second)</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td> &le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>

</properties>
