<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
<comment>Irrigation XML-ized experiment round configuration</comment>

<!--<entry key="hostname">localhost</entry>-->
<entry key="hostname">@SERVER_ADDRESS@</entry>
<entry key="port">@PORT_NUMBER@</entry>
<entry key="round0">round0.xml</entry>
<entry key="round1">round1.xml</entry>
<entry key="round2">round2.xml</entry>
<entry key="round3">round3.xml</entry>
<entry key="round4">round4.xml</entry>
<entry key="round5">round5.xml</entry>
<entry key="round6">round6.xml</entry>
<entry key="round7">round7.xml</entry>
<entry key="round8">round8.xml</entry>
<entry key="round9">round9.xml</entry>
<entry key="round10">round10.xml</entry>
<entry key="round11">round11.xml</entry>
<entry key="round12">round12.xml</entry>
<entry key="round13">round13.xml</entry>
<entry key="round14">round14.xml</entry>
<entry key="round15">round15.xml</entry>
<entry key="round16">round16.xml</entry>
<entry key="round17">round17.xml</entry>
<entry key="round18">round18.xml</entry>
<entry key="round19">round19.xml</entry>
<entry key="round20">round20.xml</entry>
<entry key="round21">round21.xml</entry>


<entry key="wait-for-participants">true</entry>
<entry key="number-of-rounds">22</entry>

<entry key="undisrupted-bandwidth">true</entry>

<entry key="q1">4</entry>
<entry key="q2">identity</entry>
<entry key="q3">49</entry>
<entry key="q4">76</entry>
<entry key="q5">4</entry>
<entry key="q6">5</entry>
<entry key="q7">25</entry>
<entry key="q8">4</entry>
<entry key="q9">25</entry>
<entry key="q10">30</entry>
<entry key="q11">1.50</entry>


<entry key="facilitator-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Facilitator Instructions</h3>
<p>
Welcome to the facilitator interface.  This interface allows you to control
the experiment.  You may only modify configuration parameters <b>before</b>
you start the experiment by selecting the Configuration menu.  When all the
participants are ready to begin the experiment, you can start the experiment
by selecting Experiment -&gt; Start.  After a round has been completed you
will be able to view the statistics for all of the participants.  You can
begin the next round by selecting Round -&gt; Start.
</p>
]]>
</entry>



<entry key="general-instructions0">
<![CDATA[
<center><h3>Welcome to the experiment.  Please do not close this window or open any
other applications.</h3></center>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions1">
<![CDATA[
<h3>General Instructions</h3>
<p>Welcome. You have already earned 5 dollars by showing up for this exercise.
You can earn more, up to an extra 25 dollars, by participating in the exercise
which will last for about one hour. You will participate in this exercise as a
part of a group. Each group has five participants. Your group has been formed
by randomly assigning you to FOUR other participants in the room. The amount
of money you earn will depend on the decisions made by you and the rest of the
group.  That is, your earnings will depend on your decisions as well as the
other members of your group.
</p>
<p>
This exercise mimics decisions people make in irrigation systems. In each round you
will receive 10 tokens which you can choose to keep or invest in the irrigation
infrastructure (for example canals and water diversion structures). Depending on the
state of repair of the irrigation infrastructure, it will be capable of directing
water to your field when you use your water diversion structure (called an
irrigation gate). Depending on the amount of water you can get to your field, you
can grow crops. Depending on the number of crops you grow you earn tokens. Each
token is worth 5 cents and you will be paid cash in private at the end of the
experiment based on the number of tokens you earned.
</p>
<p>
The experiment consists of a number of rounds. In each round you will first make a
decision as to how much to invest in the irrigation infrastructure. Without periodic
investment, the irrigation infrastructure will break down over time. Based on the
combined contributions of all 5 participants in your group in each round, as
explained below, your group can maintain the performance of the irrigation
infrastructure.  The condition of the irrigation infrastructure determines
its capacity to deliver water which you can use to grow crops. 
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq1">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
How many OTHER people in the room will be in your group?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="0">0<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="1">1<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="4">4<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="Everybody">Everybody<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions2">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Chat</h3>
<p>Each round will start with a chat period of 40 seconds where you can send text
messages to the other participants. You may discuss any aspect of the exercise.
<b>However</b>, you are <b>not allowed</b> to promise the other participants
side-payments or threaten them with any consequence after the experiment is
finished. You are also <b>not allowed</b> to reveal your real identity.  We will be
monitoring the chat traffic.  If we see any member of a group violating the rules,
we will have to remove that <b>entire group</b> from the experiment room.  That
group will have to wait until the entire experiment is finished to receive
their payment.<br><br>

You will see a text box appear on your screen when a chat period starts. The amount
of time left in the chat period will be shown at the <b>top left of the screen</b>.<br>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq2">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
Which of the following topics are you <b>not allowed</b> to discuss in chat?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="weather">the weather<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="identity">your real identity<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="experiment">the experiment<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="earnings">what you will do with the money you earn from this experiment<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions3">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Creating Irrigation Infrastructure</h3>
<p>
At the beginning of each round you and each other participant will be given 10
tokens. You must then decide what to do with these tokens. You may decide to invest
in the irrigation infrastructure or to keep the tokens.  If you keep the tokens you
will earn at a minimum 10 tokens X 5 cents = $0.50 for each round.  If you do this
every round after twenty rounds you will end up with at least $10 (plus any crops
that you may be able to grow as we will discuss later).  Your total earnings for
participating in the experiment would then be at least $10 plus your show-up fee of
$5, for a grand total of at least $15.
</p>
<p>
On the other hand, if you invest some of your tokens in the irrigation
infrastructure, you may be able to earn more than this amount by growing crops. If
the irrigation infrastructure is operating at near maximum capacity you can grow a
large crop and earn $1.50 each round.  If you grow crops you can roughly triple your
earnings compared to doing nothing. The actual earnings depend on the decisions you
and the other participants in your group make in terms of investment and when to
grow crops.
</p>
<p>
In each round the condition of the irrigation system declines such that its water
delivery efficiency drops by 25%. Investment is necessary to keep the irrigation
infrastructure from deteriorating.  If you decide to invest in irrigation
infrastructure you must decide on the amount to invest out of your initial 10
tokens. Keep in mind that the irrigation infrastructure must exceed a certain level
before you can grow crops.  The tokens invested by all participants in your group
are added together and will total up to an amount 0 and 50 tokens.  Each token
invested increases the irrigation infrastructure efficiency by one percentage point,
up to a <b>maximum of 100%</b>.  This means that if the irrigation infrastructure
efficiency is at 80% it would not make sense for your group to invest a total of 50
tokens, as any investment beyond 20 tokens would be wasted.  In the table below you
can see the water delivery capacity measured in water units per second as a function
of the condition of the irrigation infrastructure.  When the infrastructure is at
100% efficiency, 40 cubic feet of water per second (cfps) will be available.  When the
irrigation infrastructure efficiency falls below 45%, there is no capacity left for
transporting water and thus there is no water available for anyone.
</p>
<p>
Your initial irrigation infrastructure will start at 75% efficiency but <b>will
carry over from round to round</b>.  As an example, let's say that no one in a 
group invests any tokens in the first round.  The irrigation infrastructure
efficiency will be set at 75% for that first round.  The table below lists the water
delivery in cubic feet per second (cfps) corresponding to the irrigation infrastructure
efficiency.  If you look at the second to last row you can see that at 75%
efficiency the irrigation infrastructure will deliver 35 cfps.  So in the first
round the group will have 35 cfps of water available to them.
</p>
<p>
Recall that each round the irrigation infrastructure efficiency deteriorates by 25%,
so at the start of the second round the infrastructure efficiency decreases to 50%.
At this point all five members of the group decide to invest 7 tokens each.   This
increases the infrastructure efficiency by 35%, resulting in a total infrastructure
efficiency of 85%.  If you look at the table again you can see that an
infrastructure efficiency of 85% will deliver 40 cfps.
</p>
<p>
The actual amount of water that is available for the group depends on the amount of
water available. Your group might have created an irrigation infrastructure with a
capacity of 40 cfps, but due to lack of rainfall only 30 cfps is available. On the
other hand, if the infrastructure capacity allows 30 cfps and 40 cfps of water is available
to the system, only 30 cfps can be delivered.
</p>

<p>
So to recap, at the beginning of each round you will be informed of the current
irrigation infrastructure efficiency.  You will then decide how many tokens (between
0 and 10) to invest in the irrigation infrastructure.  After everybody has made
their decision, you'll be notified of the condition of the irrigation infrastructure
and the corresponding water delivery capacity.  
</p>

<b>Table 1:</b> The water delivery capacity as a function of the irrigation
infrastructure condition
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Infrastructure efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery (cubic feet per second)</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td> &le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</table>

]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq3">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following questions:<br>
<form>
Question 1:<br>
If the existing infrastructure is at 20% efficiency and if the five participants
invest a total of 29 additional tokens, what will the efficiency of the irrigation
infrastructure become?
<input type="text" name="q3" value = "">
<br><br>

Question 2:<br>
If the existing infrastructure is 50% and if two participants invest 10 tokens <b>each</b>
while the three other participants invest 2 tokens <b>each</b>, what will the
efficiency of the irrigation infrastructure become?
<br>
<input type="text" name="q4" value = "">
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit"><br>
<br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions4">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Growing crops</h3>
<p>There are FIVE participants in each group, each of which is randomly assigned to
one of the five positions, A, B, C, D or E. Below is a schematic representing the
irrigation system.  Water comes from the box to the left and the five players
are located from upstream (leftmost) to downstream (rightmost) accordingly. To
illustrate the game, assume you are in position B. The black lines represent "gates"
that you control (i.e, open and close). 	 
<p>
<img src="http://dev.commons.asu.edu/irrigation/images/irrigation-example-screenshot.jpg"><br><br>
</p>
Each round will take 50 seconds and the amount of time left in the experiment
is indicated at the top of the screen. 
<p>
<img src = "http://dev.commons.asu.edu/irrigation/images/time-remaining-screenshot.jpg"><br>
</p>
<p>
During this round you can irrigate your field.  Your earnings depend on the amount
of water you can draw onto your fields and will be explained in more detail in the
next screen.  The speed at which you can grow a crop depends on the amount of water
available to you <b>at the time that you open your gate</b>.  The maximum flow
capacity of the main canal shared by A, B, C, D, and E is forty cubic feet per second.
</p>
<p>
The maximum capacity that can flow through your gate when it is opened is
twenty-five cubic feet per second. If other people are using the canal, the water
flow available to you might be less, and it may take longer to get water to your
field (you are limited by the flow capacity of the shared canal).
</p>
<p>
The water flow capacity available for your field is shown as a number.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq4">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
What is the minimum time to grow a crop when maximum water flow capacity is available?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="4">4 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="10">10 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="25">25 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="50">50 seconds<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructions5">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Positions A,B,C,D and E</h3>
<p> The animation above illustrates how water flows to each player when their gates are opened and closed. When a player opens 
their gate, the black line will rotate to a vertical position, allowing water (represented by white balls) to flow to them.
Note that the available bandwidth downstream of a player with an open port is reduced (illustrated by narrowing of the canal).
</p>
<p>
Access to water depends on your position as shown in the window.  Water originates
in the box at the upper left part of the screen and travels to the right.  Thus,
participant A will have first access to the available water. Water not used by
participant A is then available to be used by participant B. Water not used by
participants A and B is then available for C. Water not used by participants A, B
and C is available for D. Finally, water not used by participants A, B, C and D is
available for E. You can only start growing a crop if you have water available to
your position. If water runs out during the growing period of the crop, the partial
grown crop is lost, and you need to start from scratch again. Water can run out if,
for example, one or more people upstream from your position open their gates. <b>You
can only grow a crop successfully when you have access to water for a number of
seconds without disruptions.</b>
</p>
<p>
Assume that the total irrigation capacity available is 40 cfps.  If player A opens
their gate, they will take 25 cfps from the canal, leaving 15 cfps for B and
everyone else downstream.  If A does not open the gate however, then a total of 40
cfps is left for B and everyone else downstream.
</p>
<p>
As another example, suppose that the canal system has been allowed to deteriorate so
that the total irrigation capacity available is 20 cfps.  While player A's gate is
open, no water is available for B.  If A is NOT using water, 20 cfps is available
for B.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq5">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
What is the minimum time to deliver 500 cubic feet to your field when your maximum
water flow capacity is available?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="12.5">12.5 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="20">20 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="25">25 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="50">50 seconds<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
<br><br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions6">
<![CDATA[
<h3>How to grow crops</h3>
<p>To start growing crops, click on one of the boxes labeled "Grow this crop".<br>
<p>
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/fileScreenShotNew.JPG"><br>
</p>
The crop receiving water will turn red.  When the crop is successfully grown and
harvested it the box will turn green.  If water becomes unavailable for a period of
5 seconds after starting to grow a crop, the crop will be lost and you will have to
click the button again to re-irrigate that crop.
<br>
The percentage of the water needed for the crop at any point in time is indicated by the progress bar <br>
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/fileProgressBarScreenShot.JPG"><br> 
<p>
You cannot grow multiple crops at the same time. 
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/pauseButtonScreenShot.JPG"><br> 
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq6">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
If there are 4 green boxes and one red box, how many crops have you grown and harvested successfully?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="1">1<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="4">4<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="5">5<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="10">10<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions7">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Earnings</h3>
<p>The number of tokens earned in each round depends on how many crops have been grown and harvested in that round. 
The earnings reflect the net profit of growing crops, taking into account the costs
of fertilization, labor, and equipment.  The first few crops you grow don't generate
any net profit in terms of tokens earned because your costs must be covered first.
You must have grown at last two crops before you cover your fixed costs and begin to
generate tokens as shown in the following graph.
</p>
<br>
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/fileTokenGraphScreenShot.JPG"><br> 
<p>
The amount of tokens earned by growing crops files can also be represented as the following table.
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<tr>
    <td>Number of crops grown</td>
    <td>0</td>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>2</td>
    <td>3</td>
    <td>4</td>
    <td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Tokens earned</td>
    <td>0</td>
    <td>0</td>
    <td>6</td>
    <td>22</td>
    <td>28</td>
    <td>30</td>
</tr>
</table>
Your earnings at the end of the round depend on your investment and the number of crops grown. 
Recall that you get 10 tokens to start with.  Suppose you invest 6 tokens in the irrigation
infrastructure and you grow 4 crops.  You would have earned 28 tokens from your
crops, added to your leftover tokens, i.e., 28 + (10-6) = 32 tokens.  Each token is
worth 5 cents, translating to an actual dollar amount of $1.60.<br>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructionsq7">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
If you invest 7 tokens out of the 10 tokens you start with, and you grow 3 crops, how many total tokens would you have earned that round?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="3">3<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="7">7<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="22">22<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="25">25<br>
<br><br>

If you invest 10 tokens out of the 10 tokens you start with, and you grow 5 crops, how many total tokens would you have earned that round? 
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="10">10<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="20">20<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="25">25<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="30">30<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
<br><br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions8">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Scores</h3>
<p>The total number of tokens collected during the experiment is shown as:<br>
<p>
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/tokensCollectedScreenShot.JPG"><br>
</p>
This is the total of tokens not invested in irrigation infrastructure plus the
additional tokens you've earned by growing crops<br>
You can see the scores of the other participants summarized on the screen. You can
also see the percentage of each player's water being used at any given moment,
as illustrated in the figure below.
<p>
<img src = "http://sod19.asu.edu/irrigation/images/scoreScreenShotNew.JPG"><br>
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq8">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
Each token is worth 5 cents.  If you collected 30 tokens in a round you would have earned:<br>
<input type="radio" name="q11" value="0.15">0.15<br>
<input type="radio" name="q11" value="0.50">0.50<br>
<input type="radio" name="q11" value="1.50">1.50<br>
<input type="radio" name="q11" value="2.50">2.50<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq9">
<![CDATA[
We will now start with two practice rounds. This practice round will not contribute to your earnings – 
it is intended to acquaint you with the functioning of the exercise environment.<br><br>

If you have any questions feel free to raise your hand and to ask your question.
<b>Do you have any questions so far?</b>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions-undisruptedBandwidth">
<![CDATA[
<br>
You can only start downloading a file if you have bandwidth available at your position. If the bandwidth connection 
is broken during the downloading of a file, the downloaded part of the file is lost, and you need to start from scratch 
again to download this file. The bandwidth connection can be broken if, for example, one or more people to the left of 
your position starts downloading files, using up the all available bandwidth. Only when you have continuous access to 
bandwidth without disruptions for a length of time sufficient to download an entire file can you download a file 
successfully. 
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructions11">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Invest tokens in the irrigation infrastructure</h3>
<p>
You have 10 tokens to invest. You must make a decision about how much you wish to
invest [0,10] in the irrigation infrastructure.  As a reminder we have included the
table relating irrigation infrastructure and the total available flow capacity in
the figure below. After you have entered the number of tokens you'd like to invest,
hit the enter key or click the submit button to confirm your investment. When
everybody has made their decision, the total investment will be calculated and the
overall irrigation infrastructure will be displayed.  Each token you invest
corresponds to one percent of infrastructure efficiency, so if you invest 10 tokens
you are contributing 10% to the overall infrastructure efficiency.
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Total Infrastructure Efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery (cubic feet per second)</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td> &le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>

</properties>
