<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
<comment>Irrigation experiment round configuration</comment>
<!--<entry key="hostname">localhost</entry>-->
<entry key="hostname">@SERVER_ADDRESS@</entry>
<entry key="port">@PORT_NUMBER@</entry>
<entry key="round0">round0.xml</entry>
<entry key="round1">round1.xml</entry>
<entry key="round2">round2.xml</entry>
<entry key="round3">round3.xml</entry>
<entry key="round4">round4.xml</entry>
<entry key="round5">round5.xml</entry>
<entry key="round6">round6.xml</entry>
<entry key="round7">round7.xml</entry>
<entry key="round8">round8.xml</entry>
<entry key="round9">round9.xml</entry>
<entry key="round10">round10.xml</entry>
<entry key="round11">round11.xml</entry>
<entry key="round12">round12.xml</entry>
<entry key="round13">round13.xml</entry>
<entry key="round14">round14.xml</entry>
<entry key="round15">round15.xml</entry>
<entry key="round16">round16.xml</entry>

<entry key="wait-for-participants">true</entry>
<entry key="number-of-rounds">17</entry>

<entry key="undisrupted-flow-required">true</entry>

<entry key="q1">4</entry>
<entry key="q2">identity</entry>
<entry key="q3">49</entry>
<entry key="q4">76</entry>
<entry key="q5">20</entry>
<entry key="q6">5</entry>
<entry key="q7">25</entry>
<entry key="q8">7</entry>
<entry key="q9">19</entry>
<entry key="q10">1.50</entry>

<entry key='final-instructions'>
<![CDATA[
<p>
The experiment is almost over.  We have a brief survey for you to fill out while the
facilitator prepares your payments.  When the facilitator has finished preparing
payments and you have all completed your surveys your computer number will be
called.  You can then go next door to receive your payment.  For privacy reasons we
must pay you one at a time. 
</p>
<p>
Thanks for participating!
</p>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="initial-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Welcome</h3>
<p>
Please be patient while the experimental environment is set up.  
<b>Please do not close this window or open any other windows.</b>
</p>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="facilitator-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Facilitator Instructions</h3>
<p>
Welcome to the facilitator interface.  This interface allows you to control
the experiment.  You may only modify configuration parameters <b>before</b>
you start the experiment by selecting the Configuration menu.  When all the
participants are ready to begin the experiment, you can start the experiment
by selecting Experiment -&gt; Start.  After a round has been completed you
will be able to view the statistics for all of the participants.  You can
begin the next round by selecting Round -&gt; Start.
</p>
]]>
</entry>



<entry key="general-instructions0">
<![CDATA[
<center><h3>Welcome to the experiment.  Please do not close this window or open any
other applications.</h3></center>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions1">
<![CDATA[
<h3>General Instructions</h3>
<p>Welcome. You have already earned 5 dollars by showing up for this exercise.
You can earn more, up to an extra 25 dollars, by participating in the exercise
which will last for about one hour. You will participate in this exercise as a
part of a group. Each group has five participants. Your group has been formed
by randomly assigning you to FOUR other participants in the room. The amount
of money you earn will depend on the decisions made by you and the rest of the
group.  That is, your earnings will depend on your decisions as well as the
other members of your group.
</p>
<p>
This exercise mimics decisions people make in irrigation systems. In each round you
will receive 10 tokens which you can choose to keep or invest in the irrigation
infrastructure (for example canals and water diversion structures). Depending on the
state of repair of the irrigation infrastructure, it will be capable of directing
water to your field when you use your water diversion structure (called an
irrigation gate). Depending on the amount of water you can get to your field, you
can grow crops. Depending on the number of crops you grow you earn tokens. Each
token is worth 5 cents and you will be paid cash in private at the end of the
experiment based on the number of tokens you earned.
</p>
<p>
The experiment consists of a number of rounds. In each round you will first make a
decision as to how much to invest in the irrigation infrastructure. Without periodic
investment, the irrigation infrastructure will break down over time. Based on the
combined contributions of all 5 participants in your group in each round, as
explained below, your group can maintain the performance of the irrigation
infrastructure.  The condition of the irrigation infrastructure determines
its capacity to deliver water which you can use to grow crops. 
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq1">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
How many OTHER people in the room will be in your group?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="0">0<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="1">1<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="4">4<br>
<input type="radio" name="q1" value="Everybody">Everybody<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions2">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Chat</h3>
<p>Before each round you will have a chat period of 40 seconds where you can send
text messages to the other participants. You may discuss any aspect of the exercise
with two important exceptions:
</p>
<ol>
<li>You are <b>not allowed</b> to promise the other participants
side-payments or threaten them with any consequence after the experiment is
finished.
</li>
<li>You are <b>not allowed to reveal your real identity</b>.</li>
</ol>
<p>
We will be monitoring the chat traffic.  If we detect any violation of these rules,
we will have to remove <b>all members of the group where the violation occurred</b>
from the experiment. That group will have to wait until the entire experiment is
finished to receive their payment.
</p>
<p>
You will see a text box appear on your screen when a chat period starts. The amount
of time left in the chat period will be shown at the <b>top left of the screen</b>.<br>
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq2">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
Which of the following topics are you <b>not allowed</b> to discuss in chat?<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="weather">the weather<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="identity">your real identity<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="experiment">the experiment<br>
<input type="radio" name="q2" value="earnings">what you will do with the money you earn from this experiment<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions3">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Creating Irrigation Infrastructure</h3>
<p>
After the chat period ends you and each other participant will be given 10 tokens.
You must then decide what to do with these tokens. You may decide to invest in the
irrigation infrastructure or to keep the tokens.  If you keep the tokens you will
earn at a minimum 10 tokens X 5 cents = $0.50 for each round.  If you do this every
round after twenty rounds you will end up with at least $10 (plus any crops that you
may be able to grow as we will discuss later).  Your total earnings for
participating in the experiment would then be at least $10 plus your show-up payment
of $5, for a grand total of at least $15.
</p>
<p>
On the other hand, if you invest some of your tokens in the irrigation
infrastructure, you may be able to earn more than this amount by growing crops. If
the irrigation infrastructure is operating at near maximum capacity you can earn
close to $1.50 each round.  Thus if you grow crops you can roughly triple your
earnings compared to doing nothing. The actual earnings depend on the decisions you
and the other participants in your group make in terms of investment and when to
grow crops.
</p>
<p>
In each round the condition of the irrigation system declines such that its water
delivery efficiency drops by 25%. Investment is necessary to keep the irrigation
infrastructure from deteriorating.  If you decide to invest in irrigation
infrastructure you must decide on the amount to invest out of your initial 10
tokens. Keep in mind that the irrigation infrastructure must exceed a certain level
before you can grow crops.  The tokens invested by all participants in your group
are added together and will total up to an amount 0 and 50 tokens.  Each token
invested increases the irrigation infrastructure efficiency by one percentage point,
up to a <b>maximum of 100%</b>.  This means that if the irrigation infrastructure
efficiency is at 80% it would not make sense for your group to invest a total of 50
tokens, as any investment beyond 20 tokens would be wasted.  In the table below you
can see the water delivery capacity measured in water units per second as a function
of the condition of the irrigation infrastructure.  When the infrastructure is at
100% efficiency, 40 cubic feet of water per second (cfps) will be available.  When the
irrigation infrastructure efficiency falls below 45%, there is no capacity left for
transporting water and thus there is no water available for anyone.
</p>
<p>
Your initial irrigation infrastructure will start at 75% efficiency but <b>will
carry over from round to round</b>.  As an example, let's say that no one in a 
group invests any tokens in the first round.  The irrigation infrastructure
efficiency will be set at 75% for that first round.  The table below lists the water
delivery in cubic feet per second (cfps) corresponding to the irrigation infrastructure
efficiency.  If you look at the second to last row you can see that at 75%
efficiency the irrigation infrastructure will deliver 35 cfps.  So in the first
round the group will have 35 cfps of water available to them.
</p>
<p>
Recall that each round the irrigation infrastructure efficiency deteriorates by 25%,
so at the start of the second round the infrastructure efficiency decreases to 50%.
At this point all five members of the group decide to invest 7 tokens each.   This
increases the infrastructure efficiency by 35%, resulting in a total infrastructure
efficiency of 85%.  If you look at the table again you can see that an
infrastructure efficiency of 85% will deliver 40 cfps.
</p>
<p>
The actual amount of water that is available for the group depends on the amount of
water available. Your group might have created an irrigation infrastructure with a
capacity of 40 cfps, but due to lack of rainfall only 30 cfps is available. On the
other hand, if the infrastructure capacity allows 30 cfps and 40 cfps of water is available
to the system, only 30 cfps can be delivered.
</p>

<p>
To recap, at the beginning of each round you will be informed of the current
irrigation infrastructure efficiency.  You will then decide how many tokens (between
0 and 10) to invest in the irrigation infrastructure.  After everybody has made
their decision, you will be notified of the condition of the irrigation
infrastructure and the corresponding water delivery capacity.  
</p>

<b>Table 1:</b> The water delivery capacity as a function of the irrigation
infrastructure condition
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Infrastructure efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery (cubic feet per second)</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td>&le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</table>

]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq3">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following questions:<br>
<form>
Question 1:<br>
Given an existing infrastructure efficiency of 20%, if the five participants invest
a <b>total of 29 additional tokens</b>, what is the new irrigation infrastructure
efficiency?
(<b>Note: only enter a number, you don't need to add the % sign</b>)<br>
<input type="text" name="q3" value = "">
<br><br>

Question 2:<br>
Given an existing infrastructure efficiency of 50%, if <b>two participants invest 10 tokens each</b>
while the <b>three other participants invest 2 tokens each</b>, what is the new
irrigation infrastructure efficiency?
(<b>Note: only enter a number, you don't need to add the % sign</b>)<br>
<input type="text" name="q4" value = "">
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit"><br>
<br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions4">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Growing crops</h3>
<p>There are <b>five</b> participants in each group, each of which is randomly assigned to
one of the five positions, A, B, C, D or E. Below is a screenshot of the
graphical interface representation of the irrigation system.  Water comes from
the box to the left and the five players are located from upstream (leftmost)
to downstream (rightmost) accordingly.  To illustrate, assume you are in
position C. The black lines represent "gates" that you open and close by
clicking on the large button on the lower left corner of the screen.
Each round consists of 50 seconds and the amount of time left in the
experiment is indicated by a bar at the top of the screen. 
</p>
<img src="http://dev.commons.asu.edu/irrigation/images/game-interface-screenshot.jpg">
<br><br>
<p>
You can irrigate your field during the round by opening your gate.  Your
earnings depend on the amount of water you can draw onto your fields and will
be explained in more detail on the next page.  The speed at which you can grow
a crop depends on the amount of water available to you <b>at the time that you
open your gate</b>.  The maximum flow capacity of the main canal shared by A,
B, C, D, and E is forty cubic feet per second.
</p>
<p>
The maximum amount of water that can flow through your gate when it is opened
is 25 cubic feet per second. If other people are using the canal, the water
flow available to you might be less, and it may take longer to get water to
your field since you are also limited by the amount of water that is flowing
through the shared canal.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq4">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
Question 3:<br>
<form>
What is the minimum time to deliver 500 cubic feet of water to your field when
your maximum water flow capacity is available?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="12.5">12.5 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="20">20 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="25">25 seconds<br>
<input type="radio" name="q5" value="50">50 seconds<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructions5">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Positions A,B,C,D and E</h3>
<p> 
The animation above illustrates how water flows to each player when their gates are
opened and closed. When a player opens their gate, the black line will rotate to a
vertical position, allowing water (represented by white dots) to flow to them. Note
that the water available downstream of a player with an open port is reduced,
illustrated by a narrowing of the canal.
</p>
<p>
Access to water depends on your position as shown in the window.  Water originates
in the box at the upper left part of the screen and travels to the right.  Thus,
participant A will have first access to the available water. Water not used by
participant A is then available to be used by participant B. Water not used by
participants A and B is then available for C. Water not used by participants A, B
and C is available for D. Finally, water not used by participants A, B, C and D is
available for E. 
</p>
<p>
You can only get water to your field if you have water available to your position.
Suppose that the total irrigation capacity available is 40 cfps and 40 cfps of water
is available. If player A opens their gate they will consume 25 cfps of water and 15
cfps is left for B. Suppose on the other hand, A does not open the gate, then a
total of 40 cfps is left for B, allowing B to extract water at the maximum rate of
25 cfps. 
</p>
<p>
As another example, suppose that the canal system has been allowed to deteriorate
so that the total irrigation capacity available is 20 cfps. While player A’s gate is
open, no water is available for B. If A is NOT using water, 20 cfps is available for
B.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructionsq5">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
Suppose the irrigation efficiency is between 71 and 80% so that the canal flow
capacity is 30 cfps.  If A opens their gate and diverts water at 25 cfps what is the
available water flow for B?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="30">30 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="25">25 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="15">15 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q6" value="5">5 cfps<br>
<br><br>
If the canal flow capacity available is 25 cfps and A,B,C and D are not using water,
what is the available water for E?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q7" value="40">40 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q7" value="25">25 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q7" value="15">15 cfps<br>
<input type="radio" name="q7" value="0">0 cfps<br>

<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
<br><br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions6">
<![CDATA[
<h3>How to grow crops</h3>
<p>
To start growing crops, click on the yellow button labeled &quot;open gate&quot;.
This will open your irrigation gate and allow water to flow to your field if it is
available. The text on the button will change to &quot;close gate&quot; - if
you would like to close the gate and stop extracting water from the canal, just
click on the yellow button again. Your gate will close and the text on the button
will change back to &quot;open gate&quot;.
</p>
<p>
The amount of water units (cubic feet) your field has received is shown on the
screen, as well as the resulting amount of tokens earned from growing a crop.
The number of tokens earned in each round depends on how much water you have
diverted to your field. If you receive less than 150 cubic feet (cf) the crop has
not received enough water to grow a crop and you will thus not receive any tokens.
The maximum earnings are received when between 500 cf and 549 cf are diverted to
your field. If more than 549 cf water is diverted to your field, this will
negatively affect the growth of the crop (i.e. overwatering) and less tokens will be
earned. In the table below you can see the amount of tokens earned for amount of
water applied to your field. 
</p>
<b>Table 2</b>: Earnings resulting from the amount of water applied to your field.

<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Water units received (cubic feet)</th>
<th>Tokens earned</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 150</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>150-199</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>200-249</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>250-299</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>300-349</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>350-399</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>400-499</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>500-549</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>550-649</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>650-699</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>700-749</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>750-799</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>800-849</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>850-899</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&gt; 899</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
</table>

Your earnings at the end of the round depend on your investment and the number of
tokens received for the crop.  For example, suppose you invest 6 out of the 10
tokens you are endowed with at the start of the round and you receive 333 cubic feet
of water.  Your total earnings will be the amount of tokens leftover from your
initial endowment (10 - 6) plus the tokens you earned from your crop (15 tokens for
333 cubic feet of water, see Table 2).  The total number of tokens earned is 19
($0.85 since each token is $0.05).

]]>
</entry>

<entry key='water-collected-to-tokens-table'>
<![CDATA[
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Water applied to your field</th>
<th>Tokens earned</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 150</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>150-199</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>200-249</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>250-299</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>300-349</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>350-399</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>400-499</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>500-549</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>550-649</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>650-699</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>700-749</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>750-799</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>800-849</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>850-899</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&gt; 899</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructionsq6">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
If you invest 7 of the 10 tokens you started with, and you put 202 cf of water
on your field, what is the <b>total number of tokens</b> you will have earned
for that round?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="3">3<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="5">5<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="7">7<br>
<input type="radio" name="q8" value="13">13<br>
<br><br>
If you invest all 10 tokens you start with, and you put 555 cf of water on your
field, what is the total number of tokens your will have earned for that round?
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="10">10<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="19">19<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="20">20<br>
<input type="radio" name="q9" value="29">29<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions7">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Scores</h3>
<p>
The total number of tokens collected during a round is shown on the screen with the
message:
<br><br>
Total tokens earned this round: 0
<br><br>
This the total of tokens not invested in irrigation structure plus additional
tokens earned by growing a crop.
<br>
You will also see the scores of the other participants summarized on the screen.
Finally, you will see the water flow capacity of each player at any given moment, as
illustrated in the figure below. 

]]>
</entry>


<entry key="general-instructionsq7">
<![CDATA[
<br><br>
To continue to the next page, please answer the following question:<br>
<form>
Each token is worth 5 cents, thus if you collected 30 tokens in a round you earned:
<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value=".15">$0.15<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value=".50">$0.50<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="1.50">$1.50<br>
<input type="radio" name="q10" value="2.50">$2.50<br>
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
<br><br>
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="general-instructions8">
<![CDATA[
<p>
We will now start with two practice rounds. This practice round will not
contribute to your earnings – it is intended to acquaint you with the
functioning of the exercise environment.
</p>
<p>
You will first chat via text with other participants in your group and then
decide how much you wish to invest in irrigation infrastructure maintenance.
After all investment decisions have been made you will begin the actual round
and make real-time decisions on when to open your gates and irrigate your
fields.
</p>
<p>
If you have any questions feel free to raise your hand and to ask your question.
<b>Do you have any questions so far?</b>
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="undisrupted-flow-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<p>
If the flow of water is disrupted while your gate is open your crop growing progress
will be halted.
</p>
]]>
</entry>


<entry key="investment-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Invest tokens in the irrigation infrastructure</h3>
<p>
You have been endowed with 10 tokens to invest. You must make a decision about
how much you wish to invest [0,10] in the irrigation infrastructure.  You can
see the relationship between total investment and irrigation infrastructure in
the table below.  After you have entered the number of tokens you'd like to
invest, hit the enter key or click the submit button to confirm your
investment. When everybody has made their decision, the total investment will
be calculated and the overall irrigation infrastructure will be displayed.
Each token you invest corresponds to one percent of infrastructure efficiency,
so if you invest 10 tokens you are contributing 10% to the overall
infrastructure efficiency.
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<th>Total Infrastructure Efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery (cubic feet per second)</th>
</thead>
<tr>
<td> &le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>

</properties>
