<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
<comment>Irrigation experiment server configuration</comment>
<entry key="hostname">@SERVER_ADDRESS@</entry>
<entry key="port">@PORT_NUMBER@</entry>
<entry key="round0">round0.xml</entry>
<entry key="round1">round1.xml</entry>
<entry key="round2">round2.xml</entry>
<entry key="round3">round3.xml</entry>
<entry key="round4">round4.xml</entry>
<entry key="round5">round5.xml</entry>
<entry key="round6">round6.xml</entry>
<entry key="round7">round7.xml</entry>
<entry key="round8">round8.xml</entry>
<entry key="round9">round9.xml</entry>
<entry key="round10">round10.xml</entry>
<entry key="round11">round11.xml</entry>
<entry key="round12">round12.xml</entry>
<entry key="round13">round13.xml</entry>
<entry key="round14">round14.xml</entry>
<entry key="round15">round15.xml</entry>
<entry key="round16">round16.xml</entry>
<entry key="round17">round17.xml</entry>
<entry key="round18">round18.xml</entry>
<entry key="round19">round19.xml</entry>
<entry key="round20">round20.xml</entry>
<entry key="round21">round21.xml</entry>

<entry key='quiz-pages'>2</entry>
<entry key="wait-for-participants">true</entry>
<entry key="number-of-rounds">22</entry>

<entry key="q1">49</entry>
<entry key="a1">49%</entry>
<entry key="explanation1">An existing infrastructure efficiency of 20% + 29 tokens invested = 49% infrastructure efficiency.</entry>
<entry key="q2">5</entry>
<entry key="a2">5 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation2">
<![CDATA[
An existing infrastructure efficiency of 35% + 15 tokens invested = 50% infrastructure efficiency for the current round.  
An infrastructure efficiency of 50% corresponds to a water delivery capacity of 5 cubic feet per second.
]]>
</entry>
<entry key="q3">5</entry>
<entry key='a3'>5 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation3">Since there is only 30 cubic feet per second of water available, the irrigation infrastructure capacity of 35 cubic feet per second will not be fully used.  When A opens their gate, they take 25 of the 30 cubic feet per second out of the canal, leaving 5 cubic feet per second for B.</entry>
<entry key="q4">25</entry>
<entry key="a4">25 cubic feet per second</entry>
<entry key="explanation4">If A has 25 cfps available and does not take any
water, the same amount is available for the people downstream. Since B, C and
D do not take water, 25 cfps is available for E.</entry>
<entry key="q5">7</entry>
<entry key="a5">7 tokens</entry>
<entry key="explanation5">If you invest 7 out of 10 tokens, you keep 3 tokens for yourself. If you apply 202 cubic feet of water to your field you will earn 4 tokens. 3 + 4 = 7 tokens </entry>
<entry key="q6">19</entry>
<entry key="a6">19 tokens</entry>
<entry key="explanation6">If you invest all 10 tokens, you keep 0 tokens from your initial endowment.  If you apply 555 cubic feet of water to your field you will earn 19 tokens. 0 + 19 = 19 tokens.</entry>


<!-- FIXME: lots of parameterizable fields here.  should make instructions
template-language-pluggable 
-->
<entry key="initial-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h1>Instructions</h1>
<hr>
<p>
You have already earned {showUpPayment} dollars by showing up for this exercise. You
can earn more, up to a maximum of about 25 dollars, by participating in this
experiment which will take about an hour to an hour and a half. The amount of money
you earn depends on your decisions AND the decisions of other people in this room
over the course of the experiment.
</p>
<h2>Groups</h2>
<hr>
You will be participating in this exercise as a part of a group of
{self.clientsPerGroup} participants. Your group has been formed by randomly
selecting you and four other participants in the room. 
</p>
<h2>How to participate</h2>
<hr>
<p>
This exercise mimics decisions people make in irrigation systems. In each round you
will receive {self.tokenEndowment} tokens which you can invest in the irrigation
infrastructure. Based on the <b>water delivery capacity</b> of the irrigation
infrastructure and the availability of water you will be able to grow crops. Tokens
earned in a round is the sum of tokens not invested plus tokens earned by growing
crops. Each token is worth {dollarsPerToken}. In each round you will first decide how much to
invest in the irrigation infrastructure.  Based on the combined contributions of all
5 participants in your group in each round, your group can maintain the capacity of
the irrigation infrastructure for growing crops. 
</p>

<p>
We will now start a practice round to help illustrate the experiment.  Before each
round in this experiment you will have a chat period of {self.chatDurationInMinutes}
where you can send text messages to the other participants. You may discuss any
aspect of the exercise with two important exceptions:
</p>
<ol>
<li>You are <b>not allowed</b> to promise the other participants
side-payments or threaten them with any consequence after the experiment is
finished.
</li>
<li>You are <b>not allowed to reveal your real identity</b>.</li>
</ol>
<p>
We will be monitoring the chat traffic.  If we detect any violation of these rules,
we will have to remove <b>all members of the group where the violation occurred</b>
from the experiment. That group will have to wait until the entire experiment is
finished to receive payment.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key='game-screenshot-instructions'>
<![CDATA[
<img src="http://dev.commons.asu.edu/irrigation/images/game-interface-screenshot.jpg">
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="facilitator-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<p>
    This facilitator interface allows you to control the experiment.  In general you
    will be following a sequence similar to this:
</p>
<ol>
    <li>Show instructions</li>
    <li>Start round</li>
    <li>After round is over, start standalone chat round if necessary</li>
    <li>Goto 1.</li>
</ol>
]]>
</entry>
<entry key="welcome-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<h1>Welcome</h1>
<hr>
<p>
Welcome to the experiment. We will begin shortly after everyone has been
assigned a station.
<br><br>
Please <b>wait quietly</b> and <b>do not close this window, open any other applications, or communicate with any of the other participants</b>.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="quiz-page1">
<![CDATA[
<p>
The first two questions deal with irrigation infrastructure investment.  
<b>Please refer to Table 1 of your handout</b>.
</p>

<form>
Question 1:<br>
Given an existing infrastructure efficiency of 20%, if the five participants invest
a <b>total of 29 additional tokens</b>, what is the new irrigation infrastructure
efficiency?<br>
<input type="text" name="q1" value = "">%
<br><br>

Question 2:<br>
Suppose the infrastructure efficiency in the last round was 60%.  For the current
round, the efficiency will decline by an amount of 25% for a resulting
infrastructure efficiency of 35%.  If the members of your group invest a total of 15
tokens, what will be your group's resulting water delivery capacity?<br>

<input type="text" name="q2" value = ""> cubic feet per second
<br><br>

<b>The next two questions deal with the capacity of the irrigation system in relation
to the actual amount of water available.</b>
<br><br>
Question 3:<br>
If the irrigation efficiency is between 71 and 80%, the water delivery capacity of
the irrigation system is 35 cubic feet per second.  Suppose the water supply
available to your group is 30 cubic feet per second and A opens their gate,
diverting water at 25 cubic feet per second.  What is the available water flow for
B?
<br>
<input type='text' name='q3' value=''> cubic feet per second
<br><br>
Question 4:
If the available water delivery capacity is 25 cubic feet per second and A, B, C,
and D are not using water, how much cubic feet of water per second is available for
E?<br>
<input type='text' name='q4' value=''> cubic feet per second
<br><br>

<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit"><br>
<br>

]]>
</entry>

<entry key="quiz-page2">
<![CDATA[
<p>
The final two questions cover the number of tokens you can earn in within a round.
<b>Please refer to table 2 of your handout</b>.
</p>
<form>
Question 5:<br>
If you invest 7 of the 10 tokens you start with and you apply 202 cubic feet of
water to your fields, what is the total number of tokens you will have earned at the
end of the round?<br>
<input type="text" name="q5" value="">tokens
<br><br>
Question 6:<br>
If you invest all 10 tokens you start with and you apply 555 cubic feet of water to
your fields, what is the total number of tokens you will have earned at the end of
the round?<br>
<input type="text" name="q6" value="">tokens
<br><br>
<input type="submit" name="submit" value="Submit">
</form>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key='water-collected-to-tokens-table'>
<![CDATA[
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Water applied to your field</th>
<th>Tokens earned</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 150</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>150-199</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>200-249</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>250-299</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>300-349</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>350-399</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>400-499</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>500-549</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>550-649</td><td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>650-699</td><td>18</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>700-749</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>750-799</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>800-849</td><td>4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>850-899</td><td>1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&gt; 899</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key='chat-instructions'>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Chat Instructions</h3>
You may now chat for {self.chatDurationInMinutes} with the other members of your group.  You may
discuss any aspect of the exercise with two important exceptions:
</p>
<ol>
<li>You are <b>not allowed</b> to promise the other participants
side-payments or threaten them with any consequence after the experiment is
finished.
</li>
<li>You are <b>not allowed to reveal your real identity</b>.</li>
</ol>
<p>
We will be monitoring the chat traffic.  If we detect any violation of these rules,
we will have to remove <b>all members of the group where the violation occurred</b>
from the experiment. That group will have to wait until the entire experiment is
finished to receive payment.
</p>
<p>
You can send messages by typing in the text field at the bottom of the screen
and then pressing the return key. The time left for the discussion is displayed with
a progress bar above the text field at the bottom of the screen.
</p>
]]>
</entry>

<entry key="investment-instructions">
<![CDATA[
<p>
You have been endowed with {self.tokenEndowment} tokens to invest. You must make a decision about
how much you wish to invest in the irrigation infrastructure (choosing a number
between 0 and {self.tokenEndowment}.  You can see the relationship between total
investment and irrigation infrastructure in the table below.  After you have entered
the number of tokens you'd like to invest, hit the enter key or click the submit
button to confirm your investment. When everybody has made their decision, the total
investment will be calculated and the overall irrigation infrastructure will be
displayed. Each token you invest corresponds to one percent of infrastructure
efficiency, so if you invest 10 tokens you are contributing 10% to the overall
infrastructure efficiency.
</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="2" cellpadding="2">
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Irrigation Infrastructure Efficiency (percent)</th>
<th>Water delivery capacity (cubic feet per second)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> &le; 45</td><td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>46-51</td><td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>52-55</td><td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>56-58</td><td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>59-61</td><td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>62-65</td><td>25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>66-70</td><td>30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>71-80</td><td>35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>81-100</td><td>40</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
</entry>
<entry key='client-debriefing'>
<![CDATA[
<h1>{if (self.practiceRound)}Practice Round{else}Round {self.roundNumber}{endif} Results</h1>
<hr>
    <table border=3 cellpadding=5 cellspacing=5>
        <tr>
            <th>Position</th>
            <th>Initial token endowment</th>
            <th>Tokens invested</th>
            <th>Tokens not invested</th>
            <th>Tokens earned from growing crops</th>
            <th>Total tokens earned this round</th>
            <th>Dollars earned this round</th>
            <th>Quiz earnings</th>
            <th>Total dollars earned</th>
        </tr>
        {dataModel.clientDataSortedByPriority: {clientData|
        <tr align='center' bgcolor='#{if (clientData.self)}FFFFCC{else}CCCCCC{endif}'>
            <td>{clientData.priorityString}</td>
            <td>{self.tokenEndowment}</td>
            <td>{clientData.investedTokens}</td>
            <td>{clientData.uninvestedTokens}</td>
            <td>{clientData.tokensEarnedFromWaterCollected}</td>
            <td>{clientData.allTokensEarnedThisRound}</td>
            <td>{clientData.totalDollarsEarnedThisRound}</td>
            <td>{clientData.quizEarnings}</td>
            <td>{clientData.grandTotalIncome}</td>
        </tr>
        }}
    </table>
    <h2>Earnings</h2>
    <hr>
        <p>You are in position {clientData.priorityString} and received {clientData.totalDollarsEarnedThisRound} this past round.
            Your <b>total income</b> is <b>{clientData.grandTotalIncome}</b>, including the {showUpPayment} show-up bonus.</p>
    {if (showExitInstructions)}
    <h2>Exit Survey</h2>
    <hr>
    <p>
        This was the last round, but not the end of the experiment. We ask that you please carefully fill out a brief survey as we prepare your payments.
    </p>
    <h2>Payment</h2>
    <hr>
    <p>
        When payments are ready we will call you up one by one. Please wait until
        your computer number, <b>{clientData.id}</b>, is called to turn in your
        survey and receive payment.  
        NOTE: Please <b>answer the survey completely (there may be a back side)</b>
        and <b>bring all your belongings with you</b> when you come up to receive
        your payment to help us speed up the payment process.
    </p>
]]>
</entry>
<entry key="same-as-previous-round-instructions">
    <![CDATA[
    <h3>Round {self.roundNumber} Instructions</h3>
    <hr>
    <p>Round {self.roundNumber} is the same as the previous round.</p>
    <p>The length of this round is {duration}.</p>
    <p><b>Do you have any questions?</b> If you have any questions at this time
        please raise your hand and someone will come over to your station and
        answer it.
    </p>
    ]]>
</entry>
<entry key="contribution-summary">
<![CDATA[
<h1>Contributions Summary</h1>
<hr>
<p>
Your group invested a total of <b>{groupDataModel.totalContributedTokens} tokens</b> this round, resulting in an infrastructure efficiency of <b>{groupDataModel.infrastructureEfficiency}%</b> and a water delivery capacity of <b>{groupDataModel.irrigationCapacity} cubic feet per second</b>.  
The amount of water available to pass through your canal is <b>{groupDataModel.actualWaterDeliveryCapacity} cubic feet per second</b>.
</p>
<table border=2 cellspacing=2 cellpadding=3>
<tr>
<th></th></th><th>Infrastructure Efficiency</th><th>Water Delivery Capacity</th><th>Water Availability</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Before Investment</td><td>{groupDataModel.infrastructureEfficiencyBeforeInvestment}%</td><td>{groupDataModel.irrigationCapacityBeforeInvestment} cubic feet per second</td><td>{groupDataModel.actualWaterDeliveryCapacity}</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>After Investment</td><td>{groupDataModel.infrastructureEfficiency}%</td><td>{groupDataModel.irrigationCapacity} cubic feet per second</td><td>{groupDataModel.actualWaterDeliveryCapacity}</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]>
</entry>
</properties>
